（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
（笑脸拍打）
(smiley snapping)
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
- 什么是域适配？
- What is domain adaptation?
在新数据集上微调预训练模型时，
When fine-tuning a pre-trained model on a new dataset,
我们适配新的数据集所获得的微调模型
the fine-tuned model we obtain will make predictions
将做出预测。
that are attuned to this new dataset.
当两个模型用相同的任务训练时，
When the two models are trained with the same task,
我们可以使用相同的输入比较他们的预测结果。
we can then compare their predictions on the same input.
两个模型的预测结果
The predictions of the two models will be different
会以一种方式反映
in a way that reflects the differences
两个数据集之间的差别
between the two datasets,
就是我们称之为域适配的现象。
a phenomenon we call domain adaptation.
让我们通过带有版本微调
Let's look at an example with masked language modeling
比较预训练的 DistilBERT 模型的输出
by comparing the outputs of the pre-trained DistilBERT model
看一个和掩码语言建模相关的例子
with the version fine-tuned
该内容在课程的第 7 章中，链接如下。
in chapter 7 of the course, linked below.
预训练模型进行通用预测，
The pre-trained model makes generic predictions,
而微调模型
whereas the fine-tuned model
它的前两个预测与电影有关。
has its first two predictions linked to cinema.
由于它是基于电影评论数据集上进行了微调，
Since it was fine-tuned on a movie reviews dataset,
因此它像这样调整它的推荐结果
it's perfectly normal to see
是完全正常的。
it adapted its suggestions like this.
注意它作为之后的预训练模型
Notice how it keeps the same prediction
如何保持相同的预测。
as the pre-trained model afterward.
即使微调后的模型适应了新的数据集，
Even if the fine-tuned model adapts to the new dataset,
它不会遗失预先训练的内容。
it's not forgetting what it was pre-trained on.
这是翻译任务的另一个例子。
This is another example on a translation task.
在上面的代码里，我们使用预训练的法语 / 英语模型，
On top, we use a pre-trained French/English model,
在下面的代码里，是我们在第 7 章中微调的版本。
and at the bottom, the version we fine-tuned in chapter 7.
上面的模型在大量文本上进行了预训练，
The top model is pre-trained on lots of texts,
并保留了英文中的技术术语，
and leaves technical English terms,
像 plugin 和 email 这样的单词，是不会被翻译的。
like plugin and email, unchanged in the translation.
法国用户都可以很好地理解两者。
Both are perfectly understood by French people.
为微调模型选择的数据集是
The dataset picked for the fine-tuning is a dataset
一个包含技术文本的数据集
of technical texts where special attention was picked
其中特别将所有内容都翻译为法语。
on translating everything in French.
结果，经过微调的模型适应了该特征
As a result, the fine-tuned model picked that habit
并翻译了 plugin 和 email 两个词。
and translated both plugin and email.
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)